Sid Zhang

iOS / macOS Developer Born 1989 Live in Melbourne





About me

I've been developing iOS Apps since 2010 and I love making Apps. Apple made a short movie named "Apocalypse" in WWDC2017 which shows why Apps are so important to everyone.

Link: Apocalypse

Skills

9 years iOS 1 year macOS

Swift Objective-C

zhangxi.me

Arduino

Mandarin/English



Contact

Murrumbeena

✓ sid.zhang.oz@gmail.com

0457396355

ttps://sidzhang.me

zhangxigithub



Experience

macOS Developer

QSR International January 2020 - Now Develop NVivo for macOS

macOS Developer

Evernote China

September 2018 - December 2019

Evernote span out its China-based unit into an independent entity with "full autonomy" over its business and services since June 2018.

https://www.yinxiang.com

iOS Developer

ChinaSo

May 2013 - September 2018

iOS Developer

KuXun Travel (TripAdvisor China)

December 2011 - May 2013

I was the first iOS Engineer in this company. We developed Apps that sale train ticket, flight ticket and hotel rooms.



Education

Bachelor of Computer Science and Technology September 2008 - June 2012

Major in Computer Science and Technology, YanTai University, China.

Projects

Evernote

mac_{OS}

We developed some excited new functions such as Sticky Note, WeChat Login, Team Space, Todo list, New Editor, etc.

ChinaSo

iOS

The app is used for searching news.

Personal Apps

I uploaded my first iOS App to App Store in December 2010. I love to convert my thought to apps.

More projects can be found here. https://sidzhang.me/projects



Others

Arduino

I like both software and hardware. I like making something funny with Arduino. https://youtu.be/DsFWsGPrE-M

Cocoacontrols

Some tools used by myself.

https://www.cocoacontrols.com/authors/zhangxigithub

RSBarCode

RSBarCode is an open source project I did with my ex-collegue many year ago. https://github.com/yeahdongcn/RSBarcodes

iOS 9 Years I have been developing iOS Apps since 2010. I have developed different types of Apps in

different companies but there is no essential difference. Many Apps can no longer be

downloaded for many reasons, but the development experience is retained.

macOS The work of the past year has been macOS Apps development. MacOS Apps

development is very similar to iOS Apps development. The experience of macOS

development can make me better understand the Apple platform.

Swift 5 years I have been using Swift in my project since the beginning of swift come out. The biggest

trouble is that you have to keep learning, Swift has evolved quickly and is constantly

changing.

Hardware (I love it) I like to develop on multiple platforms, especially to get them working together. Here are

some funny things I did.

Raspberry Pi / iPhone, Control cam with iPhone (2014)

Demo: https://youtu.be/jO9UvEWKTSI

Arduino / Mac, Play Wachat game (2018)

Github: https://github.com/zhangxigithub/Wechat_Jump

Demo: https://youtu.be/y332n1p0jYY

Arduino/Mac Laser engrave (2018)

Github: https://github.com/zhangxigithub/Engrave

Demo: https://youtu.be/QS3dhQe4ah0

Evernote Hackathon / Arduino / Mac , Control Evernote create note (2019)

Demo: https://youtu.be/oQejBYK90-c

Fire truck, Toy for my son (2017)
Demo: https://youtu.be/4XLzqcFuizl

Agile All the companies I have worked with use Agile / Jira / Scrum.

CI Jenkins

Ul Storyboard / Auto Layout

Keep UI and business logic code separate and minimise coupling.

Networking HTTP / Bluetooth / Bonjour / Socket

Use Codable / SwiftyJSON parse JSON

Bluetooth: https://apps.apple.com/au/app/heart-monitor/id1214803994?mt=12

Bonjour: https://github.com/zhangxigithub/Bonjour

QSR 1/2020 - now

macOS Developer

Australian Company https://www.qsrinternational.com

Mac App / Swift / Objective-C

2 months contract. The company's development team is in Vietnam and needs

developers to implement some key functions.

I have completed UI update for welcome screen, new seamless activation.

Evernote 2018 - 2019

macOS Developer

Mac App / Swift / CoreData / Thrift / Jenkins

My responsibility is to develop some new features such as sticky notes, to-dos, WeChat

login, etc.

ChinaSo 2014 - 2018

iOS Developer

Swift / Carthage / WKWebView

I worked for this company for 5 years and participated in all projects.

The main project is a news App, which use the RESTful API to return data from the CMS,

and displays it with WebView.

Kuxun 2011 - 2014

iOS Developer

Objective-C / ARC / SQLite(FMDB)

This is my first company but it no longer exists.

I interned here before graduating and then joined this company after graduation. I am the

first iOS developer here.

Personal Apps

I often develop some Apps for myself, and I like to use applications to solve problems. For example, I need to take a driver's license, but Vicroads's learner practice webpage is too difficult to use, so I use a spider to grab the data of Vicroads and made an iOS app.

Learner permit test: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/learnerpermittest-vicroads/

<u>id1394422855?ls=1&mt=8</u>

All my personal Apps: https://apps.apple.com/au/developer/zhang-xi/id408188278